# **CARLOS HERNÁNDEZ**

# FRONT-END / PRODUCT DESIGNER

México City

© Text me

in LinkedIn

Portfolio

I know, I have an atypic profile, but that doesn't mean I haven't the capacity to do the job or learn new stuff.

I worked several years in administrative area, I'm a fast-learning person, even unknowing design I learned quickly, I don't want a routine I want enjoy what I'm doing, so believe me when I say I found my vocation, all my jobs leaved me a knowledge so I learned to develop soft skills trough years like manage my emotions, work under pressure, active listen and assertive communication to be better.

#### Soft skills

Decision making | Team work | Focus on results | Self-learning | Effective communication | Leadership | Creativity | Ethic

#### Tech skills

HTML5 | CSS3 | SCSS | JS | PHP (Cake) | OOP | Node JS | Bootstrap | React (Intermediate) | Figma | Git | Github | VSC | Zeplin

### Languages

· Spanish - Native

• English - B2

# Professional experience

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER / PRODUCT DESIGNER Adryo

Jul 2022 - Sep 2023

- UX: Define sprints, delivery times and objectives for the different areas, benchmarks, quantitative and qualitative analysis, use of agile methodologies (Scrum, Design thinking, Lean UX), define tasks according to priority, identify usability improvements based on heuristics, user interviews to obtain findings and improvements.
- UI: Creation of color palette, wireframes, mockups on med and high resolution, prototype, user flows, design system.
- Front: Creation of components, forms, buttons to use on platform and responsive view, improve usability and functionality with best practices, create new functional modules, make it intuitive by following business rules and sticking to the existing UI in figma.

**UX-UI DESIGNER** Mar 2022 - May 2022

#### Zion Transaccional

- UX: Analyze websites and improvement usability, based on heuristics.
- UI: Creation of color palette, design structure on figma, protoype and redesign mobile apps and websites.
- · Web: Redesign websites in WordPress.
  - · Create NomiYa! mobile app and web responsive dashboard.
  - · Redesign of Mobile app Dezba.
  - · Re design of UBOX solutions on WP.

#### **UX-UI / WEB DESIGNER**

Mar 2020 - Jul 2022

# Colectivo Tlacuache Urbano

- UX: Research, empathy map, user journeys, user surveys and website wireframe.
- UI: Website prototyping in figma.
- Web: Website creation in WordPress.

# **UX-UI / WEB DESIGNER**

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

#### Mundo Xochimilco

- UX: Research, market research.
- Web: Website creation in WordPress.

# Education

DEV.F Ninja UX /UI	2020 - 2021	SEO WordPress	Jan 2021
DEV.F Master UX /UI	2021 - 2022	Introduction to UX	May 2021
DEV.F Master en Coding	2022 - 2023	LEAN UX	Jul 2021
		Figma	Jul 2021
		Design Thinking	Aug 2021
		HTML y CSS	Aug 2021